

# Nikita Lindemann Data Scientist



Russian Federation, Moscow



lindemann.nikita@gmail.com



nikita-lindemann



Skills -

Deep Learning

Machine Learning

Python

PyTorch

Confluence

Jira

Agile (Scrum, Kanban)

Git

Linux

Docker

SQL

C++

## Profile

Graduate of MIPT, 5 years of experience working with machine learning models, data preparation and training neural networks. Use of various convolutional neural network architectures to solve CV problems, integration of developed modules. Experience in the full cycle of developing video analytics systems - from purchasing equipment to supporting the system in production.

Experience in backend development in Python: development of client-server applications (asyncio, threads, multiprocessing, flask) and modules for working with devices, development of module architecture and analytics modules. Working with pipes and shared memory, writing wrappers for C++ code (ctypes). Experience in Linux environments.

MLOps experience (ML pipeline development): deployment, configuration and monitoring of modules using python, systemd, ansible, docker, SQL.

Experience in the production of ML-like solutions (products based on ML/CV/NLP technologies), derivation of a machine learning ML model beyond the MVP stage.

Practical experience with version control systems and project management systems (Jira, Confluence) in team development.

Knowledge and experience in using Agile methodology (scrum, kanban). Knowledge of CI/CD.

## Education

2018 - 2023 Bachelor of Mathematics and Physics Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology Department of Control and Applied Mathematics

## Experience

2019-2020 Junior Data scientist. MIPT Cognitive Dynamic Systems Lab

- 1. Collected and labeled data for computer vision tasks.
- 2. Developed computer vision systems for self-driving vehicles using convolutional neural networks.
- 3. Solved the problem of classifying road scene objects (traffic lights and road signs).
- 4. Developed classification module and successfully implemented in the competition of self-driving vehicles "Winter City".

2021-2023 ML CV Engineer, Deputy Head of Department. Glosav

- 1. Developed video analytics systems.
- Solved problems of classification, detection and tracking using CNN.
- 3. Developed infrastructure for integrating video analytics systems.
- 4. Optimization and integration of convolutional neural networks on mini PCs (jetson, firefly) using ONNX, TensorRT, RKNN.
- Developed, supported and integrated the following modules: license plate recognition, vehicle detection and classification, face detection and classification, vehicle tracking, lidar data capture, vehicle dimensions calculation.
- Developed and successfully implemented a face recognition and people counting system for VDNKH (Moscow subway station) with a load more than 2000 people per hour.
- 7. Developed and successfully implemented an intelligent system for collecting tolls on the federal highways M1 and M4 with a load more than 5000 vehicles daily.
- 8. Compilation of technical specifications and setting tasks for developers and engineers, analysis of the necessary equipment (mini PCs, cameras, sensors, etc.) and preparation of technical specifications for purchasing department, communication with customers. Participation in the process of hiring and training new employees.

#### 2023-2024 Senior Data Scientist. Cloud.ru

- 1. Development of a platform for holding machine learning championships: forming hypotheses for product development, testing, user support.
- 2. Establishing and setting up championships, creating virtual environments and docker images for launching user submissions.
- 3. Development of ML pipelines (AI services), including in express mode (MVP development, verification/testing of hypotheses), preparation of EDA using Python libraries on client data.
- 4. Formalization of needs and the formation of business requirements, expert quality control of the resulting ML models, achieving the customer's business goals.
- 5. The system for calculating user submission metrics has been refactored.
- 6. More than 10 championships of various levels with a total prize fund of more than 100 million rubles were successfully held.
- 7. 5 benchmarks from various industries were launched: Construction and housing and communal services, Industry, Transport, Agro-industrial complex, Healthcare.

#### Courses

2019-2020 Neural Networks, Mail.ru

2019-2022 Machine learning and math teacher at HSE, Sber, MIPT

# Languages

Russian Native speaker

English B2/C1